Cheney Brothers Silk Manufacturing Company Records 1984.0026
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Cheney Brothers Silk Manufacturing Company Records
undated, 1734 - 1979
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1984.0026
136.25 Linear Feet
In 1838, six Cheney brothers established the Mount Nebo Silk Company in Manchester, CT. The company adopted the family name in 1843. Aided by booming national markets, a protective tariff, and innovative production methods, the company grew into the nation's largest and most profitable silk mill by the late 1880s. The company pioneered the wastesilk spinning method and the Grant's reel. The company reached its peak in 1923, after which it quickly declined due to industry wide overproduction and competition from new synthetic fibers such as rayon. Although it revived slightly during World War II, the family sold the company to J. P. Stevens and Company in 1955. J. P. Stevens quickly liquidated the equipment and the remainder was sold to Gerli Incorporated of New York. In 1978, the mills and surrounding neighborhood were declared a National Historical Landmark District. The mill was permanently closed in 1984. Most of the mill buildings were sold to developers who converted them into luxury apartments and offices.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Acquisition Information
The employee records and other materials were donated by Gerli and Company to the University of Connecticut in April 1984. Included in this original donation were personnel records, employee record cards, union negotiations materials, fabric samples and photographs.
The Cheney Brothers Silk Manufacturing Company financial and executive records, including minutes of Director's meetings and account books, were donated by the Connecticut Historical Society in October 1984.
Arrangement
Series I: Administrative Records (undated, 1734-1979).
Subseries A: Minutes of Meetings of the Board of Directors (1854-1936).
Subseries B: History of the Cheney Brothers (1734-1955).
Subseries C: Employee Relations (undated, 1920-1970).
Subseries D: National and Regional War Labor Records (1942-1946).
Subseries E: Wage Stabilization Boards (1946-1952).
Subseries F: Government Contract Work (1937-1956).
Subseries G: Inter-Office Memoranda (1912-1924)
Subseries H: Sales Records (1950-1954).
Subseries I: Printed Material (1903-1979).
Series II: Personnel Records (1900-1962).
Subseries A: Subject Files (1942-1962).
Subseries B: Accidents (1920-1956).
Subseries C: Wages (1920-1962).
Subseries D: Hiring Specifications (circa 1925-1963).
Subseries E: Employee Record Cards (1860-1960).
Series III: Labor Relations Records (1930-1974, bulk dates 1938-1953).
Subseries A: Arbitration (1930-1974).
Subseries B: Agreements and Contracts (1934-1956).
Subseries C: Arbitration Cases/Awards (1930-1953).
Subseries D: Disputes (1920-1951).
Subseries E: Local 63 (1934-1955).
Subseries F: Supreme Court of errors (1951-1954).
Subseries G: Arbitration Local 63 (1938-1974).
Subseries H: Laws (undated, 1947-1954).
Series IV: Production samples (undated, 1925-1955).
Series V: General Accounts (1847-1927).
Series VI: Blueprints (undated, 1891-1959).
History
In 1838, six Cheney brothers established the Mount Nebo Silk Company in Manchester, CT. The company adopted the family name in 1843. Aided by booming national markets, a protective tariff, and innovative production methods, the company grew into the nation's largest and most profitable silk mill by the late 1880s. The company pioneered the waste-silk spinning method and the Grant's reel.
At the beginning of World War I, the company employed over 4,700 workers. One out of every four Manchester residents worked at the Cheney Mills in some capacity. The company was an integral part of the community, its domain taking in over 175 acres, including mills buildings, churches, houses, schools, recreation centers, utility companies, and even a railroad. The company was also known nationally for its benevolent system of welfare capitalism. It was one of the first textile mills to use Frederick Taylor's methods of scientific management.
In its early years, the company relied mostly on native-born American labor, but throughout the late 19th and early 20th centuries, the company actively recruited both skilled and unskilled immigrant labor. By the 1920s, foreign worker dominated the labor force.
The company reached its peak in 1923, after which it quickly declined due to industry-wide overproduction and competition from new synthetic fibers such as rayon. During the Depression, the company was forced to borrow heavily to keep the mills running. In 1933, it sold its rail lines and utility companies. The 1930s was also a period of increased labor strife. The company successfully resisted unionization until 1934 when it was forced to accept the United Textile Workers as the bargaining representative of the workers. The company was forced to declare bankruptcy in 1937.
The Second World War brought a temporary recovery in the form of silk parachute production for the war effort; however, after the war, outmoded plant facilities, high labor costs, and strong competition from southern mills forced the Cheney family to sell the company to the textile giant, J. P. Stevens & Company in 1955. J. P. Stevens quickly sold off or destroyed most of the machinery and equipment which produced goods competitive with other Stevens-owned mills. Cheney Brothers was eventually sold to Gerli Incorporated of New York. In 1978, the mills and surrounding neighborhood were declared a National Historical Landmark District.
The mills lingered on in this truncated condition until 1984 when it was closed permanently. Most of the mill buildings were sold to developers who converted them into luxury apartments and offices.
Additional historical information is located in the collection file. Please contact a staff member for further information.
Custodial History
J. P. Stevens & Company deposited financial and executive records at the Connecticut Historical Society in 1964.
Scope and Content
The collection contains materials relevant to the production and sale of silk—administrative, financial, production and employee records, in addition to fabric samples, publications, reports and photographs.
The administrative files contain minutes, historical information on the founding of the company and its growth, company produced handbooks and manuals, employee publications, sales records and a variety of publications related to textiles and labor. These files also contain information pertaining to government contract work, wages, and inter-office communications.
Personnel records contain information about Pioneer Parachute Company, a subsidiary, and its efforts to recruit employees during World War II and the early 1950s. Other files concern the cafeteria arrangements of the company, reinstated union employees and the forgery case of Henry de Wald, a company employee. Monthly and yearly accident tabulations, reports and related documents are included in this series as are wages, hiring specifications and employee records. The specifications materials describes equipment, materials and duties connected with each position within the Ribbon, Spinning and Dressing departments and the Throwing mill. Each position description includes a black and white photograph (circa. 1920s) showing the appropriate machine and its operator. The employee records cards contain detailed personal information on all non-management employees (1900-1960).
The labor files contain materials relevant to the Mill and its interaction with Local 63 of the Textile Workers Union of America. Also included are publications and information pertaining to federal labor laws and newspaper clippings.
Textile manufacturers; New York (inhabited place); Photographs; Textile workers; Textile industry; Arbitration, Industrial; World War (1939-1945); World War (1914-1918); Manpower; Economic history; Silk; Industrial accidents; Hours of labor; Financial Records; Labor unions; Connecticut (state); Reports; Actions and defenses; Publications (documents); Silk industry; Correspondence; Employees; Parachutes; United States (nation); Industrial relations; Labor; Law; Blueprints (reprographic copies).; Legislation; Industrial mobilization; Cheney, Ralph, 1806-1897; Cheney, Frank, 1817-1904; Cheney, Charles, 1803-1874
- Series I: Administrative Records, 1734-1968
  - Subseries A: Minutes of Meetings of the Board of Directors, 1854-1936
    - 1854 July - 1894 July (Box 1)
    - 1894 October - 1910 February (Box 2)
    - 1910 March - 1914 December (Box 3)
    - 1915 February - 1920 December (Box 4)
    - 1921 January - 1928 December (Box 5)
    - 1929 January - 1936 March (Box 6)
    - Director's meeting minutes transcripts, 1854-1894 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Copies of the votes of Board of Directors, 1921-1928 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Subseries B: History of the Cheney Brothers, undated, 1734-1955
    - Historical background, 1734-1910 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Outline of historical data—World War II, 1941-1945 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Liberty loans, 1917-1919 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Personnel, historical, 1834-1919 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Wage history, 1843-1923 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Use and occupancy insurance, 1925-1955 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Transit insurance, 1952-1955 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - History of silk by Cheney Brothers, 1885-1916 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Chronique et Croquis de la Mode Novelle, 1923-1930 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Cheney Brothers on the history of fabrics and style, 1918-1924 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Manchester Businessman's Association, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - International Silk Exposition, New York, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Silk exhibit at the main hall, Cheney Brothers, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Souvenir program, Cheney Brothers headquarters, NY, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Closing of cravat department, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Inventory of records, 1928-1955 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Chart of accounts, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Textile industry, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Subseries C: Employee Relations, undated, 1920-1970
    - "The Miracle Workers" (recruitment), 1920 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - 1838 (employee magazine), 1920-1923 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Supervisor's manual, 1947-1970 (Box 7, Folder 24-26)
    - Service department book of information, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - First aid manual, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Mutual Aid Society, Cheney Brothers, 1936-1955 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Safety program, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Employee Retirement Program meeting minutes, 1948-1956 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Employee Retirement Plan, Trust Agreement and Group Insurance Plan (brochure), 1945-1953 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Subseries D: National and Regional War Labor Boards, 1942-1946
    - National presidential executive orders, 1942-1946 (Box 7:, Folder 33)
    - National general orders and releases, 1942-1945 (Box 7:, Folder 34)
    - Cases—cotton and rayon, 1944 (Box 7:, Folder 35)
    - Regional approvable rates, 1943 (Box 7:, Folder 36)
    - Regional Correspondence, 1943-1945 (Box 7:, Folder 37)
    - Approvable wage rates—dyeing and finishing, 1944 (Box 7:, Folder 38)
    - Approvable wage rates—metal trades, 1943 (Box 7:, Folder 39)
    - Awards dates—case numbers, 1944 (Box 7:, Folder 40)
    - Quarterly bonus, 1945 (Box 7:, Folder 41)
    - Awards (Box not specified)
      - Revised vacation policy, 1945 (Box 8:, Folder 42)
      - Pack department—waxing operation, 1945 (Box 8:, Folder 43)
      - $0.55 minimum—weekly rate employees, 1945 (Box 8:, Folder 44)
      - Harness builders and loom changeover, 1945 (Box 8:, Folder 45)
      - Shearers, 1945 (Box 8:, Folder 46)
      - $0.55 minimum—hourly rate employees, 1945 (Box 8:, Folder 47)
      - Sewing machine instructors, 1945 (Box 8:, Folder 48)
      - Vacation policy, 1945 (Box 8:, Folder 49)
      - Quilling machine repairmen, 1945 (Box 8:, Folder 50)
      - Roll painter, 1944 (Box 8:, Folder 51)
      - Revision of special pay rates, 1944 (Box 8:, Folder 52)
      - Velvet weaving, 1944-1945 (Box 8:, Folder 53)
      - Print room, 1944 (Box 8:, Folder 54)
      - Sheet metal workers, 1944 (Box 8:, Folder 55)
      - Bonus to piece work, 1944 (Box 8:, Folder 56)
      - Steaming, 1945 (Box 8:, Folder 57)
      - Engraving-pantograph, 1944-1945 (Box 8:, Folder 58)
      - Velvet weaving, 1941-1943 (Box 8:, Folder 59)
      - B. G. loomfixers and smashpiecers, 1943 (Box 8:, Folder 60)
      - Auxiliary division, 1943 (Box 8:, Folder 61)
      - Velvet loomfixers, 1943 (Box 8:, Folder 62)
      - Steamfitter/plumber/auxiliary division, 1944-1945 (Box 8:, Folder 63)
      - Watchmen/auxiliary division, 1944 (Box 8:, Folder 64)
      - Auxiliary department, 1943 (Box 8:, Folder 65)
      - Folding room, 1944 (Box 8:, Folder 66)
    - Worksheets, changeover from bonus to piece work, 1942-1945 (Box 8:, Folder 67)
    - Stevenson Jordan & Harrison, 1943-1945 (Box 8:, Folder 68)
    - War Labor Disputes Act, 1942 (Box 8:, Folder 69)
    - Connecticut panel, 1944-1946 (Box 8:, Folder 70)
    - National—New England Provision Company, 1944 (Box 8:, Folder 71)
    - National—Westinghouse Electric and Manufacturing Co., 1944 (Box 8:, Folder 72)
  - Subseries E: Wage Stabilization Board, 1946-1952
    - National
      - Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 8:, Folder 73)
      - General plant increased, 1946 (Box 8:, Folder 74)
      - Velvet loomfixers, 1946 (Box 8:, Folder 75)
      - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 8:, Folder 76)
      - Awards, 1946 (Box 8:, Folder 77)
      - Pioneer Parachute Company, 1946 (Box 8:, Folder 78)
    - Regional
      - Engravers, 1952 (Box 8:, Folder 79)
      - General increase, 1951-1952 (Box 8:, Folder 80)
      - Cost of living allowance, 1951 (Box 8:, Folder 81)
      - Long service bonus, 1953 (Box 8:, Folder 82)
      - Yarn dye weavers, 1952 (Box 8:, Folder 83)
      - $0.05 increase and $0.70 minimum, 1946 (Box 8:, Folder 84)
      - Decisions, 1951 (Box 8:, Folder 85)
      - Wage stabilization orders and interpretations, 1944 (Box 8:, Folder 86)
      - Salary stabilization board, 1951-1952 (Box 8:, Folder 87)
      - SSB Group insurance plan, 1952 (Box 8:, Folder 88)
  - Subseries F: Government Contract Work, 1937-1956
    - Contract work, 1937-1938 (Box 8:, Folder 89)
    - Industrial security letters, 1955 (Box 8:, Folder 90)
    - Defense Production Act, 1950 (Box 8:, Folder 91)
    - Bureau of Aeronautics, 1956 (Box 8:, Folder 92)
    - Blank forms, 1950 (Box 8:, Folder 93)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1956 (Box 8:, Folder 94)
    - Clearances pending, 1955 (Box 8:, Folder 95)
    - Clearances received, 1947-1956 (Box 8:, Folder 96)
    - Form NN1-140, 1942 (Box 8:, Folder 97-98)
    - Posters, 1942-1950 (Box 8:, Folder 99)
    - Alien visitors—permission requests, 1950-1953 (Box 8:, Folder 100)
    - Statement of citizenship, 1943 (Box 8:, Folder 101)
    - Classified material, 1950 (Box 8:, Folder 102)
    - Personnel security questionnaire—guards Aliens, 1943 (Box 8:, Folder 103)
      - By department, 1940-1941 (Box 8:, Folder 104)
      - Clearances applied for/received, 1949-1955 (Box 8:, Folder 105-106)
      - Miscellaneous, 1942-1943 (Box 8:, Folder 107)
      - Form P-36 acknowledgment, 1942-1945 (Box 8:, Folder 108-110)
    - War Department—Army, Air Force, 1942-1945 (Box 9:, Folder 111)
    - Contract Work, 1954-1955 (Box 9:, Folder 112)
    - Bureau of Aeronautics representative, 1948-1952 (Box 9:, Folder 113)
    - War Department contracts, 1947-1949 (Box 9:, Folder 114)
    - Navy Department contracts, 1947-1950 (Box 9:, Folder 115)
    - General information, 1947-1949 (Box 9:, Folder 116)
  - Subseries G: Inter-Office Memoranda, 1912-1924
    - Notices and policy letters, 1912-1922 (Box 9:, Folder 117)
    - Inter-office memoranda, 1950-1959 (Box 9:, Folder 118-120)
    - Mill letters (1 to 200), 1912-1924 (Box 10:, Folder 121)
  - Subseries H: Sales Records, 1950-1954
    - 1950 (Box 10:, Folder 122)
    - 1951 (Box 10:, Folder 123)
    - 1952 (Box 10:, Folder 124)
    - 1953 (Box 10:, Folder 125)
    - 1954 (Box 10:, Folder 126)
  - Subseries I: Printed Materials, 1903-1979
    - "Bylaws of the Silk Association", 1903 (Box 11:, Folder 127)
    - Harper's Weekly New York industrial issue, 1911 (Box 11:, Folder 128)
    - American Silk Journal, 1928 (Box 11:, Folder 129)
    - Cheney Brothers' advertisement, 1925 (Box 11:, Folder 130)
    - Textile Manufacturers Journal, 1928 (Box 11:, Folder 131)
    - "The Work of Edgar Brandt in New York" [see also box 59], undated (Box 11:, Folder 132)
    - Manchester, USA, 1977 (Box 11:, Folder 133)
    - Silk, 1928 (Box 11:, Folder 134)
    - Connecticut vacation guide, 1979 (Box 11:, Folder 135)
    - "The Silk Industry of American Census", 1902 (Box 11:, Folder 136)
    - "Census of Manufacturers: Connecticut", 1905 (Box 11:, Folder 137)
    - Service chart of fabrics and colors, 1925 (Box 11:, Folder 138)
    - Congressional Record, Hawley-Smoot Tariff, 1930 (Box 11:, Folder 139)
    - "The 3 phase system for mass production", 1926 (Box 11:, Folder 140)
    - "Work Assignment", 1936 (Box 11:, Folder 141)
    - "Annual report of the Silk Association", 1909, 1920 (Box 11:, Folder 142)
    - "Brief of the Silk Association", 1921 (Box 11:, Folder 143)
    - "The New Age Discrimination Law", 1968 (Box 11:, Folder 144)
    - "Reference guide to the Fair Labor Standards Act", 1963, 1966 (Box 11:, Folder 145)
    - Workmen's compensation manual, 1914 (Box 11:, Folder 146)
    - "Connecticut Uniform Commercial guide", 1961 (Box 11:, Folder 147)
    - The Transition from School to Work, 1968 (Box 11:, Folder 148)
    - Union Contract Clauses, 1954 (Box 11:, Folder 149)
    - American Arbitration by Frances Kellor, 1948 (Box 11:, Folder 150)
    - Materials Research Chronology, 1962 (Box 11:, Folder 151)
- Series II: Personnel Records, 1860-1962
  - Subseries A: Subject Files, 1942-1962
    - James Hurley, recruiter, 1943-1952 (Box 12:, Folder 152-157)
    - Pioneer cafeteria and house, 1943-1951 (Box 12:, Folder 158-159)
    - Chestnut Lodge inventory, 1943-1945 (Box 12:, Folder 160)
    - Henry DeWald forgery case, 1952 (Box 12:, Folder 161-162)
    - Cheney cafeteria, 1951-1955 (Box 12:, Folder 163)
    - Golden Commissary Corp. cafeteria, 1950-1951 (Box 12:, Folder 164)
    - Housing—rents, 1948-1952 (Box 12:, Folder 165)
    - Group insurance, 1956 (Box 12:, Folder 166)
    - Employee's retirement plan, 1956-1957 (Box 12:, Folder 167)
    - Payroll adds/drops/changes, 1956 (Box 12:, Folder 168)
    - Reinstate union employees, 1955-1962 (Box 12:, Folder 169-170)
    - Service honor rolls, 1942-1946 (Box 12:, Folder 171)
  - Subseries B: Accidents, 1920-1956
    - Monthly reports, 1942-1946 (Box 12:, Folder 172)
    - Tabulation, 1947-1958 (Box 12:, Folder 173-174)
    - Medical department charge slips, 1956 (Box 12:, Folder 175)
    - Reports and tabulations, 1955 (Box 12:, Folder 176)
    - Reports for lost time case—Aetna, 1935-1937 (Box 12:, Folder 177-178)
    - Statutory accidents, 1926-1932 (Box 12:, Folder 179-180)
    - Monthly record charts, 1956-1957 (Box 12:, Folder 181)
    - Aetna tabulation sheet, 1950-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 182)
    - Monthly record charts, 1954-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 183)
    - National Safety Council, 1947 (Box 12:, Folder 184)
    - Yearly report—U.S. Department of Labor, 1939 (Box 12:, Folder 185)
    - Quarterly reports—U.S. Department of Labor, 1939 (Box 12:, Folder 186)
    - Yearly accident record charts, 1945-1948 (Box 12:, Folder 187)
    - Safety certificates, 1953 (Box 12:, Folder 188)
    - To All Superintendents, 1946-1955 (Box 12:, Folder 189)
    - Inter-office correspondence, 1943-1950 (Box 12:, Folder 190)
    - Cases, 1935-1957 (Box 12:, Folder 191)
    - Follow up cases, 1934-1938 (Box 12:, Folder 192)
    - Dermatitis cases, 1944-1947 (Box 12:, Folder 193)
    - Man-hours—accident reports, 1945-1950 (Box 12:, Folder 194)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1942-1952 (Box 12:, Folder 195)
    - Reports—Aetna, 1942 (Box 13:, Folder 196)
    - Injury reports—War Department, 1943-1944 (Box 13:, Folder 197)
    - Workmen's Compensation Commission, 1920-1926 (Box 13:, Folder 198)
  - Subseries C: Wages, 1920-1962
    - Average hourly earning by department, 1943-1957 (Box 13:, Folder 199-220)
    - Wages paid for half-time due to overtime, 1940-1955 (Box 13:, Folder 221)
    - Wages paid for shift differential, 1949-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 222)
    - Hourly rate, 1937 (Box 13:, Folder 223)
    - Comparative earnings, 1929-1934 (Box 13:, Folder 224)
    - Record of the number of employees on payroll, 1920-1955 (Box 13:, Folder 225)
    - Average hourly earnings by male and female, 1946-1951 (Box 13:, Folder 226)
    - Earning sheets, 1933-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 227-228)
    - Record of transparent velvet commissions, 1933-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 229)
    - Discontinued operations, 1942-1952 (Box 13:, Folder 230)
    - Earnings records, 1955-1962 (Box 13:, Folder 231)
    - Textile industry wages, 1950-1955 (Box 13:, Folder 232-235)
    - Northern Textile Association wage negotiations, 1956 (Box 13:, Folder 236)
    - Plant increases and revised rates, 1942-1952 (Box 13:, Folder 237)
    - Employees or departments not paid 10-20% wages for hours 11 p.m. - 7 a.m., 1951 (Box 13:, Folder 238)
    - Timekeeping department, 1956 (Box 13:, Folder 239)
    - Throwing department, 1956 (Box 13:, Folder 240)
    - Plant adjustment--$0.75 minimum, 1946 (Box 13:, Folder 241)
    - Wage adjustment, 1928-1937 (Box 13:, Folder 242-244)
    - Plant wage increase, 1956 (Box 13:, Folder 245)
    - Plant wage adjustment, 1951 (Box 13:, Folder 246)
    - Plant wage increase--$0.01 cost of living, 1951 (Box 13:, Folder 247)
    - Plant wage increase—minimum $1.15 per hour, 1951 (Box 13:, Folder 248)
    - Wage hour inspection, 1950 (Box 13:, Folder 249)
    - Plant wage increase—minimum $1.10 per hour, 1950 (Box 13:, Folder 250)
    - Plant wage adjustment—minimum $1.00 per hour, 1948 (Box 13:, Folder 251)
    - Plant wage adjustment—minimum--$0.90 per hour, 1948 (Box 13:, Folder 252)
    - Dye and finishing, 1943-1955 (Box 13:, Folder 253-256)
    - B. G. weaving, 1942-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 257-261)
    - Yarn dye, 1956 (Box 13:, Folder 262)
    - Auxiliary, 1929-1956 (Box 14:, Folder 263-265)
    - Velvet, 1943-1956 (Box 14:, Folder 266-274)
  - Subseries D: Hiring Specifications, circa 1925-1963
    - Job analysis, 1955-1963 (Box 15:, Folder 275)
    - Hiring specifications, ca. 1925 (Box 15:, Folder 276-279)
  - Subseries E: Employee Record Cards, 1860-1960
    - John Sutherland's sample (Box 16)
      - A-H, 1860-1940 (Box-folder 16:1, Box-folder 16:2)
      - I-M (Box-folder 16:4, Box-folder 16:3)
      - N-Z (Box-folder 16:5, Box-folder 16:6)
    - Employee record cards, 1900-1920
      - A - Camp (Box 17)
      - Campe - Eri (Box 18)
      - Erw - Goz (Box 19)
      - Gra - Let, 1984-0026/SeriesII/SubseriesE/Box20 (Box 20)
      - Leu - Mur, 1984-0026/SeriesII/SubseriesE/Box21 (Box 21)
      - Mus - Rue, 1984-0026/SeriesII/SubseriesE/Box22 (Box 22)
      - Ruf - Tod, 1984-0026/SeriesII/SubseriesE/Box23 (Box 23)
      - Tok - Z, 1984-0026/SeriesII/SubseriesE/Box24 (Box 24)
    - Male employee record cards, 1900-1940
      - A - Brou, 1984-0026/SeriesII/SubseriesE/Box25 (Box 25)
      - Brow - Dey, 1900-1940; 1984-0026/SeriesII/SubseriesE/Box26 (Box 26)
      - Dia - Gol, 1984-0026/SeriesII/SubseriesE/Box27 (Box 27)
      - Goo - Jol, 1900-1940; 1984-0026/SeriesII/SubseriesE/Box28 (Box 28)
      - Jon - Mas, 1984-0026/SeriesII/SubseriesE/Box29 (Box 29)
      - Mat - Osa (Box 30)